{"name": "A10 2017-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. A marble will be randomly selected from a bag of solid-colored marbles. The probability of selecting a red marble is . The probability of selecting a blue marble is . What is the probability of selecting a red marble or a blue marble?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. The graph below shows the number of students who were present on Thursday from each of the 5 groups in Ms. Meagan\u2019s class. What is the probability that a student selected at random from the class on Thursday is in Group 4 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Consider the equation . For what value of  is the value of  equal to 40 ?", "choices": {"A": "-10", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "56"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. What is |3 - x| when x = 8 ?", "choices": {"A": "-11", "B": "-5", "C": "5", "D": "8", "E": "11"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. When Tyrese fell asleep one night, the temperature was 24\u00b0 F. When Tyrese awoke the next morning, the temperature was -16\u00b0 F. Letting + denote a rise in temperature and \u2014 denote a drop in temperature, what was the change in temperature from the time Tyrese fell asleep until the time he awoke?", "choices": {"A": "-40\u00b0 F", "B": "-8\u00b0 F", "C": "+4\u00b0 F", "D": "+8\u00b0 F", "E": "+40\u00b0 F"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. Ming purchased a car that had a purchase price of \uff045,400, which included all other costs and tax. She paid  \uff041,000 as a down payment and got a loan for the rest of the purchase price. Ming paid off the loan by making 28 payments of \uff04200 each. The total of all her payments, including the down payment, was how much more than the car\u2019s purchase price?", "choices": {"A": "\uff04200", "B": "\uff041,200", "C": "\uff044,400", "D": "\uff045,600", "E": "\uff046,600"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. Shown below is a regular hexagon inscribed in a circle whose radius is 4 inches. What is the perimeter, in inches, of the hexagon?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "18", "D": "20", "E": "24"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. The floor plan for an L-shaped storage building is shown below with distances marked in feet. What is the floor area of the building, in square feet?(Note: Walls in this building meet only at right angles.)", "choices": {"A": "190", "B": "504", "C": "1,232", "D": "1,496", "E": "1,980"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Quadrilateral ABCD with vertices A(-2,0), B(0,4), C(5,5), and D(8,2) will be graphed in the standard (x, y)coordinate plane below.Which of the following is a type of quadrilateral determined by these vertices?", "choices": {"A": "Kite", "B": "Parallelogram", "C": "Trapezoid", "D": "Rectangle", "E": "Square"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Given that  and g(x)=, what is the value of ?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "19", "C": "31", "D": "152", "E": "180.5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. At her hot dog stand, Julie sells hot dogs for \uff042 each. Purchasing hot dogs and other supplies costs \uff04200 per month. The solution of which of the following inequalities models the numbers of hot dogs, h, Julie can sell per month and make a profit?", "choices": {"A": "h-200\uff1e0", "B": "h-200\uff1c0", "C": "h+200\uff1e0", "D": "2h-200\uff1c0", "E": "2h-200\uff1e0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. In the standard(x, y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line 3x+8y=5 ?", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "3", "E": "5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. Which of the following(x, y) pairs is the solution for the system of equations x+2y=2 and -2x+y=16 ?", "choices": {"A": "(-6,4)", "B": "(-1,1.5)", "C": "(1,0.5)", "D": "(0,1)", "E": "(2,0)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. On a map, inch represents 16 actual miles. Two towns that are  inches apart on this map are how many actual miles apart?", "choices": {"A": "11", "B": "16", "C": "44", "D": "64", "E": "176"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Which of the following matrices is equal to  \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. What is the value of tan A in right triangle \u25b3ABC below?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. Tina runs at a rate of 8 miles per hour. At that rate, how many miles will she run in 12 minutes?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "2"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. A function  is defined as . What is ?", "choices": {"A": "-324", "B": "-54", "C": "54", "D": "108", "E": "324"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. In the figure below, A is on and C is on . What is the measure of \u2220ABC?", "choices": {"A": "24\u00b0", "B": "42\u00b0", "C": "45\u00b0", "D": "48\u00b0", "E": "66\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. Marcos programs his calculator to evaluate a linear function, but he doesn\u2019t say what the function is. When 5 is entered, the calculator displays the value 2. When 15 is entered, the calculator displays the value 6. Which of the following expressions explains what the calculator will display when any number, n, is entered?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "n-3", "D": "n-9", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. On Friday, the temperature at 8:00 a.m. was 49\u00b0F and rose at a constant rate of per hour until noon. A cold front passed through at noon, and the temperature then fell at a constant rate of 1\u00b0F per hour. The temperature first fell below 49\u00b0F between:", "choices": {"A": "noon and 1 p.m.", "B": "1 p.m. and 2 p.m.", "C": "2 p.m. and 3 p.m.", "D": "3 p.m. and 4 p.m.", "E": "4 p.m. and 5 p.m."}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. Letter grades in Hugo\u2019s math class are based on the percent of the total possible points on 4 unit exams (each worth 100 points) and the final exam (worth 200 points) and are assigned according to the chart below.The number of points Hugo scored on the unit exams this term were 82, 88, 91, and 83. When course grades were posted, Hugo\u2019s course grade was listed as a B. Which of the following could NOT have been the number of points he scored on the final exam?", "choices": {"A": "136", "B": "156", "C": "166", "D": "176", "E": "196"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Use the following information to answer questions 23-25.Halle is bowling a series of 3 games. She has bowled 2 of 3 games with scores of 148 and 176. The figure below is a top view of the bowling lane. The dimensions for the bowling lane are given in the figure. The pin deck is the rectangular area within the bowling lane where the 10 bowling pins are set up.(Note: The figure is not drawn to scale.)23. The diameter of each pin at its base is 2.25 in. When all of the pins are set up, which of the following values is closest to the area, in square inches, that is covered by the bases of the pins?", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "71", "C": "111", "D": "125", "E": "159"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. Use the following information to answer questions 23-25.Halle is bowling a series of 3 games. She has bowled 2 of 3 games with scores of 148 and 176. The figure below is a top view of the bowling lane. The dimensions for the bowling lane are given in the figure. The pin deck is the rectangular area within the bowling lane where the 10 bowling pins are set up.(Note: The figure is not drawn to scale.)24. What is the ratio of the total area of the bowling lane to the area of the pin deck?", "choices": {"A": "12:1", "B": "13:1", "C": "13:12", "D": "127:17", "E": "137:17"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. Use the following information to answer questions 23-25.Halle is bowling a series of 3 games. She has bowled 2 of 3 games with scores of 148 and 176. The figure below is a top view of the bowling lane. The dimensions for the bowling lane are given in the figure. The pin deck is the rectangular area within the bowling lane where the 10 bowling pins are set up.(Note: The figure is not drawn to scale.)25. What score will Halle need to earn in her 3rd game to have an average score of 172 for the 3 games?", "choices": {"A": "165", "B": "172", "C": "182", "D": "192", "E": "200"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. The area of a rectangle is 300 square meters, and its length is 3 times its width. How many meters wide is the rectangle?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "30", "C": "50", "D": "100", "E": "150"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. A parallelogram has a perimeter of 96 inches, and 1 of its sides measures 16 inches. If it can be determined, what are the lengths, in inches, of the other 3 sides?", "choices": {"A": "16, 16, 48", "B": "16, 24, 24", "C": "16, 32, 32", "D": "16, 40, 40", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Elmhurst Street is a two-way street. In each direction, it has one 12-foot-wide lane for car traffic, one 6-foot-wide bike lane, and one 8-foot-wide parking lane. How many feet wide is Elmhurst Street?", "choices": {"A": "26", "B": "38", "C": "52", "D": "60", "E": "80"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. At Central High School, 4 out of every 10 students ride the bus to and from school, and 3 out of every 8 who ride the bus are freshmen. If there are 2,500 students at Central, how many of the students are freshmen who ride the bus?", "choices": {"A": "375", "B": "412", "C": "428", "D": "561", "E": "705"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. If and , then ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Given , what is(are) the real value(s) of  for which ?", "choices": {"A": "-1 only", "B": "2 only", "C": "-2 and 1 only", "D": "-1 and 2 only", "E": "1 and 2 only"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Use the following information to answer questions 32-35.In the figure below, a highway rest area (at D) and radar stations (at A and B) lie on a level east-west line; A is 9,000 feet due west of D. An airplane (at C) is shown directly above the rest area, flying due west at a constant speed of 300 feet per second and at a constant altitude of 12,000 feet. The airplane is located at a straight-line distance of 15,000 feet from the radar station at A and 13,000 feet from the radar station at B.32. Which of the following values is closest to the distance, in feet, between the 2 radar stations?", "choices": {"A": "5,000", "B": "10,000", "C": "10,500", "D": "14,000", "E": "15,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Use the following information to answer questions 32-35.In the figure below, a highway rest area (at D) and radar stations (at A and B) lie on a level east-west line; A is 9,000 feet due west of D. An airplane (at C) is shown directly above the rest area, flying due west at a constant speed of 300 feet per second and at a constant altitude of 12,000 feet. The airplane is located at a straight-line distance of 15,000 feet from the radar station at A and 13,000 feet from the radar station at B.33. Let A, C, and D lie in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane such that A is at (0,0) and D is at (9,000, 0). Which of the following equations represents the line along which the airplane is flying?", "choices": {"A": "x=9,000", "B": "x=15,000", "C": "y=12,000", "D": "y=13,000", "E": "y=15,000"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Use the following information to answer questions 32-35.In the figure below, a highway rest area (at D) and radar stations (at A and B) lie on a level east-west line; A is 9,000 feet due west of D. An airplane (at C) is shown directly above the rest area, flying due west at a constant speed of 300 feet per second and at a constant altitude of 12,000 feet. The airplane is located at a straight-line distance of 15,000 feet from the radar station at A and 13,000 feet from the radar station at B.34. Which of the following values is closest to the number of seconds it will take for the airplane to fly from C to the point directly above the radar station at A ?", "choices": {"A": "17", "B": "30", "C": "40", "D": "43", "E": "50"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Use the following information to answer questions 32-35.In the figure below, a highway rest area (at D) and radar stations (at A and B) lie on a level east-west line; A is 9,000 feet due west of D. An airplane (at C) is shown directly above the rest area, flying due west at a constant speed of 300 feet per second and at a constant altitude of 12,000 feet. The airplane is located at a straight-line distance of 15,000 feet from the radar station at A and 13,000 feet from the radar station at B.35. When considering the changing triangle formed by A, B, and the moving airplane (C), which of the angles below increases in measure as the airplane flies due west beyond the point directly above A ?I. \u2220AII.\u2220BIII.\u2220C", "choices": {"A": "I only", "B": "II only", "C": "I and II only", "D": "I and III only", "E": "II and III only"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Troy made a rectangular poster that is 4 feet long and 2 feet wide. The poster is too large to fit in the available display space, so Troy is going to make a new poster that will have an area that is 50% of the area of the original poster. The length of Troy\u2019s new poster will be  the length of the original poster. How many feet wide will the new poster be?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "3", "E": "6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. What is the solution set of the equation x+6=2(x+3)-x?", "choices": {"A": "The empty set (no solution)", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "The set of all real numbers"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Steve plans to use 28 feet of fencing to enclose a region of his yard for a pen for his pet rabbit. What is the area, in square feet, of the largest rectangular region Steve can enclose?", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "45", "C": "48", "D": "49", "E": "196"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. There are exactly 5 people in a bookstore at 12:00 p.m. Each person earns an annual income that is between\uff0430,000 and \uff0435,000. No one enters or leaves the bookstore until 12:15 p.m., when a professional athlete with an annual income of more than\uff041,000,000 enters the bookstore and joins the other 5 people. The mean, median, range, and standard deviation of the annual incomes of the 5 people in the bookstore at 12:00 p.m. are calculated and compared to the same 4 statistics of the annual incomes of the 6 people in the bookstore at 12:15 p.m. If it can be determined, which of the 4 statistics changed the least?", "choices": {"A": "Range", "B": "Mean", "C": "Median", "D": "Standard deviation", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Ana and Amy started a landscaping job together. When Ana stopped, she had completed  of the job. When Amy stopped, she had completed of the job. Then Ruben completed the rest of the job in 2 hours. Assume that Ana, Amy, and Ruben all worked at the same rate. Which of the following values is closest to the number of hours it would have taken 1 of them to complete the entire job alone?", "choices": {"A": "0.37", "B": "1.27", "C": "2.73", "D": "5.00", "E": "7.50"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. If a and b are positive real numbers, which of the following is equivalent to ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. To become a contestant on a quiz show, a person must correctly order 4 rock stars by age, from youngest to oldest. The contestant knows which one is the oldest  rock star, but randomly guesses at the order of the other 3 rock stars. What is the probability the contestant will get all 4 in the correct order?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "4x+6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. An automobile license plate number issued by a certain state has 6 character positions. Each of the first 3 positions contains a single digit from 0 through 9. Each of the last 3 positions contains 1 of the 26 letters of the alphabet. Digits and letters of the alphabet can be repeated on a license plate. How many different such license plate numbers can be made?", "choices": {"A": "36", "B": "46,656", "C": "1,000,000", "D": "12,812,904", "E": "17,576,000"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The function y=f(x) is graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. The points on the graph of the function y=3+f(x-1) can be obtained from the points on y=f(x) by a shift of:", "choices": {"A": "1 unit to the right and 3 units up.", "B": "I unit to the right and 3 units down.", "C": "3 units to the right and 1 unit up.", "D": "3 units to the right and 1 unit down.", "E": "3 units to the left and 1 unit down."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. When what is x ?", "choices": {"A": "-32", "B": "-25", "C": "-10", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. Which of the following lists those integer values of D for which the fraction  lies between  and  ?", "choices": {"A": "4 only", "B": "3, 4, and 5", "C": "8 only", "D": "7, 8, and 9", "E": "16 only"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. For all real numbers a, b, and c such that  a\uff1ed  and c\uff1c0, which of the following inequalities must be true?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "\\frac{b}{c}\">", "C": "ac\uff1ebc", "D": "a+c\uff1cb+c", "E": "a\uff1cb-c"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The triangle shown below has side lengths 37, 38, and 39 inches. Which of the following expressions gives the measure of the largest angle of the triangle?(Note: For every triangle with sides of length a, b, and c that are opposite \u2220A, \u2220B, \u2220C, respectively, )", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Pete has an average score of exactly x points on 4 equally weighted tests. How many points higher than x must Pete score on the 5th equally weighted test to raise his average score after the 5th test to x+2 points?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": "5", "D": "8", "E": "10"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. The intersection of lines l and m forms the 4 angles \u2220A, \u2220B, \u2220C, and \u2220D. The measure of \u2220B is  times the measure of \u2220A. Which of the following values is closest to the measure of \u2220A ?", "choices": {"A": "20\u00b0", "B": "26\u00b0", "C": "35\u00b0", "D": "40\u00b0", "E": "51\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. A sequence is defined for all positive integers by  and . what is  ?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "18", "C": "22", "D": "49", "E": "111"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. If a is an integer less than -1, which of the following orders the expressions , , and from least value to greatest value?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. At the school carnival, Ann is playing a game involving a stack of 10 index cards. Each card has a single number written on it: 1 card has a 1, 2 cards have a 2, 3 cards have a 3, and 4 cards have a 4. Ann will choose 1 card at random, and she will be awarded the number of points equal to the number written on the card. Let the random variable X represent the number of points Ann receives on any 1 draw. What is the expected value of X ?", "choices": {"A": "0.4", "B": "1", "C": "2.5", "D": "3", "E": "4"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. Which of the following is equivalent to the sum of any 3 consecutive odd integers, x, y, and z, such that ?", "choices": {"A": "3z", "B": "3y", "C": "3x", "D": "3x+2", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. The mean of the set of 5 numbers   is is 24, and the median of the set of 4 numbers  is 38. If it can be determined, which of the following values is equal to x-y ?", "choices": {"A": "-38", "B": "-10", "C": "10", "D": "38", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Consider all rectangles such that the rectangle\u2019s length is greater than the rectangle\u2019s width and the length and width are whole numbers of inches. Which of the following perimeters, in inches, is NOT possible for such a rectangle with an area of 144 square inches?", "choices": {"A": "48", "B": "60", "C": "80", "D": "102", "E": "148"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. The equation  is that of a circle that lies in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. One endpoint of a diameter of the circle has y-coordinate 11. What is the y-coordinate of the other endpoint of that diameter?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "8"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. The plans for a diving pool call for a rectangular prism that has a length of 30 meters, a width of 25 meters, and a depth of 5 meters. If the plans are changed to increase both the length and the width of the pool by 10%, what will be the increase, to the nearest 1%, in the volume of the pool?", "choices": {"A": "10%", "B": "17%", "C": "20%", "D": "21%", "E": "33%"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. One solution of the equation is x=-1. Which of the following describes the other 2 solutions?", "choices": {"A": "Both are negative real numbers.", "B": "One is a negative real number, and the other is a positive real number.", "C": "Both are positive real numbers.", "D": "One is a positive real number, and the other is a complex number that is not real.", "E": "Both are complex numbers that are not real."}, "correct": "E"}]}